Passion Brought Them Together... Only Success Could Tear Them Apart!
Up Close & Personal is a drama, romance film directed by Jon Avnet.
Tally Atwater has a dream: to be a prime-time network newscaster.
She pursues this dream with nothing but ambition,
raw talent and a homemade demo tape.
Warren Justice is a brilliant, hard edged, veteran newsman.
He sees Tally has talent and becomes her mentor.
Tally’s career takes a meteoric rise and she and Warren fall in love.
The romance that results is as intense and revealing as television news itself.
Yet, each breaking story, every videotaped crisis that brings them
together, also threatens to drive them apart...
Warren Justice, played by Robert Redford.
Tally Atwater, played by Michelle Pfeiffer.
Marcia McGrath, played by Stockard Channing.
Bucky Terranova, played by Joe Mantegna.
Joanna Kennelly, played by Kate Nelligan.
Ned Jackson, played by Glenn Plummer.
Up Close & Personal is a 1996 American romantic drama film directed by Jon Avnet
from a screenplay written by Joan Didion and John Gregory Dunne.
It stars Robert Redford as a news director and Michelle Pfeiffer as his protégée, with
Stockard Channing, Joe Mantegna, and Kate Nelligan in supporting roles.
The screenplay began as an adaptation of Golden Girl: The Story of Jessica Savitch, a 1988 book by
Alanna Nash that recounted the troubled life of American news anchor Jessica Savitch.
The finished picture, however, was greatly altered by commercial decisions on the part
of the producers, and bore little resemblance to Savitch's biography.
Dunne, having spent eight years working on the script with his wife Didion, later wrote a book
describing his difficult experience, titled Monster: Living Off the Big Screen.
"Because You Loved Me", the film's theme song written by Diane Warren and performed by
Celine Dion, was nominated for Best Original Song at the 69th Academy Awards.
The film explores themes of career, miami,
florida, affectation, reporter, candid.
The tone is emotional and intense.